Anna Hyatt Huntington Papers
Anna Hyatt Huntington Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Chatham College (Pittsburgh, Penn.) (Box 16)
  - Cheney, Charles Henry (Box 16)
  - Chew, Benjamin (Box 16)
  - Choate, Nathaniel (Box 16)
  - Christ Church Parish (Box 16)
  - City Club of New York (Box 16)
  - Clark, Bayard (Box 16)
  - Clark, Charles Upson (Box 16)
  - Clark, James Lippitt (Box 16)
  - Clark University (Worcester, Mass.) (Box 16)
  - Clasgens, Emma (sister of Frederic Clasgens) (Box 16)
  - Clearwater Art Museum (Box 16)
  - Clement, Jean H. (Box 16)
  - Clews, Marie (Mrs. Henry), includes photograph of Henry Clews (Box 16)
  - Close, Marjorie (Box 16)
  - Coad, Clara Carter Hyatt, AHH's sister-in-law, Alpheus III's widow; remarried J. Allan Coad (Box 16)
  - Code, Marion (Box 17)
  - Coker, David R. and May (Box 17)
  - Colamussi, Fabrizio (Box 17)
  - Colby College (Box 17)
  - Cole, Thomas Carilear (Box 17)
  - Cole, Timothy (Box 17)
  - Collins, Godfrey (Box 17)
  - Columbia College (Box 17)
  - Columbia Museum of Art (Box 17)
  - Columbia University (Box 17)
    See also Butler, Nicholas Murray (Box 15).
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 17)
  - Connecticut Park and Forest Commission (Box 17)
  - Connecticut Republican Finance Committee (Box 17)
  - Connecticut State Police (Box 17)
  - Connell, Lizzie (Box 17)
  - Conrow, Wilford S. (Box 17)
  - Conway, Francis M., includes photograph of Conway family (Box 17)
  - Cook, Doris
    - "Woman Sculptor Anna Hyatt Huntington", manuscript and photos (Box 17)
    - Research material (Box 17)
  - Cook, Edmund D. (Box 17)
  - Cook, Katherine Mayor, See Townsend, Katherine Mayor Cook (Box 55)
  - Cook, Peggy and Ernest (Box 17)
  - Cook, Ridgeley W. and Carol (Box 17)
  - Cook, Walter W. S. (Box 17)
  - Cooke, Julia (Box 17)
  - Coolidge, John, See Fogg Art Museum (Box 32).
  - Cooper-Pritchard, A.H. (Box 17)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art (Box 17)
  - [Brother] Cornelius (Box 17)
  - Cornell University (Box 17)
  - Corning, H. K. (Box 17)
  - Cortissoz, Royal (Box 17)
  - Cosgrave, John O'Hara (Box 17)
  - Cosmopolitan Club (Box 17)
  - Costarelli, Emilie Conger, See Hayward/Huntington/IBM Mediterranean exhibit (Box 35).
  - Council of American Artist Societies, See Reilly, Frank (Box 52).
  - Cram, Ralph Adams (Box 17)
  - Cresson, Margaret French (Box 17)
  - Cross, W. Redmond, See American Geographical Society (Box 8) and New York Zoological Society (Box 49).
  - Cross, Wilbur L. (Box 18)
  - Cruikshank, Helen (Box 18)
  - Cruset, Sebastian (Box 18)
  - Cuba (Box 18)
  - Cummer Gallery of Art (Jacksonville, Fla.) (Box 18)
  - Cummings, Ida (Box 18)
  - Curran, Charles C. (Box 18)
  - C, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Daingerfield, Marjorie (Box 18)
  - Dall, Charles Whitney (Box 18)
  - Damrosch, Walter (Box 18)
  - Danbury Hospital (Box 18)
  - Danbury Scott-Fanton Museum and Historical Society, Inc. (Box 18)
  - Dario, Ruben, includes typescript of essy, "Ruben Dario in New York" (Box 18)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution (Box 18)
  - Davies, Monica Borglum (daughter of Solon) (Box 18)
  - Davila, Carlos and Mrs. (Frances Adams) (Box 18)
  - Davis, Bette, clippings about her as nude model for "Young Diana" (Box 18)
  - Davis, Wendell, See Brookgreen Gardens: General (Boxes 11-13).
  - Dayton Art Institute (Box 18)
  - Decker, Benton Weaver (Box 18)
  - De Kalb, Courtenay and Frances (Box 18)
  - Deerhounds
    - American Kennel Club (Box 19)
    - Articles and clippings (Box 19)
    - Awards
      - 1930, 1935-1939, 7 folders (Box 19)
      - 1939-1940, 4 folders (Box 20)
      - 1940-1942, 5 folders (Box 21)
      - 1941-1944, 1946-1949, 8 folders (Box 22)
      - 1950-1952, 6 folders (Box 23)
      - 1953-1955, 4 folders (Box 24)
      - Undated (Box 24)
    - Calendars (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1963; undated (Box 25)
      See also Hartley, Norah (Box 34).
    - Deerhound Club of America (Box 25)
    - "Deerhounds in History" project
      - Clippings (Box 25)
      - Photographs, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Excerpts about dogs (Box 25)
    - Excerpts about dogs, 6 folders (Box 26)
    - Maps to Stanerigg (Box 26)
    - Prints (of Stanerigg dogs), 13 packages (Box 27)
    - Publicity, clippings, articles, advertisements for Stanerigg (Box 27)
    - Records
      - American Kennel Club (Box 27)
      - Championships (Box 28)
      - Individual dogs (Box 28)
      - Lists of dogs (Box 28)
      - Lists of dogs sold (Box 28)
      - Lists of dogs sold [??] (Box 28)
      - Litters (Box 28)
      - Shows, 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Studs and matrons (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
    - "Rod, Beloved Dog, Dies" (Box 29)
    - Scottish Deerhound Club of America (Box 29)
    - Scrapbooks
      - Clippings and photos, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Photos of Stanerigg dogs (Box 29)
      - Photos of Stanerigg dogs (Box 30)
    - Show bulletins (Box 30)
    - Stanerigg Kennels
      See:
      Memorabilia: Scrapbooks: Stanerigg (Box 83)
      Photographs: Family property: Stanerigg (Box 98)
      Photographs: Family property: Stanerigg[?] (Oversize 1)
    - Weese, C. Nelson, See Scottish Deerhound Club of America (Box 29)
    - "Why I chose deerhounds" by AHH (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, clippings, mostly about dog health; misc printed material (Box 30)
  - Delano, William Adams (Box 31)
  - De Lue, Donald (Box 31)
  - Demarest, Eda Lord (Box 31)
  - De Milhau, Zella (Box 31)
  - Deming, William Champion, includes photograph (Box 31)
  - Denby, Elizabeth R. (Mrs. Edwin) (Box 31)
  - Derujinsky, Gleb W. (Box 31)
  - DeVinne Press (Box 31)
  - Dewey, John (Box 31)
  - Dewey, Thomas E. (Box 31)
  - M.H. De Young Memorial Museum (Box 31)
  - Dielman, Ernest, includes original of poem used at Brookgreen Gardens (Box 31)
  - Dietsch, Clarence Percival (Box 31)
  - Dillon, Philip R. (Box 31)
  - Dmitri, Ivan, See West, Levon (Box 57).
  - Dodd, Loring Holmes, See Clark University (Box 16).
  - Doerr, Harriet (Box 31)
  - Dole, Margaret Fernald (Box 31)
  - Dondero, George A., See United States Congress (Box 56).
  - Downey, Fairfax (Box 31)
  - Doyle, Henry Grattan (Box 31)
  - Doyle, Joseph A. (Box 31)
  - Drake, Francis A. (Box 31)
  - Dreher High School (Box 31)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. (Box 31)
  - Drew, Dorothy (Box 31)
    See also Research and Security Corporation (Box 52).
  - Dufek, George, See Mariner's Museum: Minutes (Box 44).
  - Duke of Alba, See Alba, Jacobo Stuart Fitz-James y Falco, ducque de (Box 7).
  - Dunwiddie, Charlotte (Box 31)
  - Durant, William West (Box 31)
  - Duveen, Joseph (Box 31)
  - D (Box 31)
  - Eames, Emma (Box 31)
  - East Carolina College (Greenville, North Carolina) (Box 31)
  - Eberle, Abastenia St. Leger (Box 31)
  - Education Information, Inc. (Box 31)
  - Egler, Frank E. (Box 31)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box 31)
    See also Photographs: People: Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Oversize 1).
  - Eldredge, Charles (Box 31)
  - Eliscu, Frank (Box 31)
  - Engel, Arthur (Box 31)
  - Erwin, Ellen (Box 31)
  - Escandon y Barron, Jose Manuel, marquis de Villavieja (Box 31)
  - Espina, Concha (Box 31)
  - Evans, Cerinda W., photograph only
    See also Mariners' Museum: General (Box 43) for her correspondence.
  - Evans, Rudolph (Box 31)
  - Evansville Museum of Art and Science (Evansville, Ind.) (Box 32)
  - E (Box 32)
  - Fairbanks, Avard (Box 32)
  - Farrar, John (Box 32)
  - Federal Art Project (Box 32)
  - Fenwick-Wilson, May [Mary?] (Box 32)
  - Ferguson, Elise (Mrs. Homer) (Box 32)
  - Ferguson, Homer L., See Mariners' Museum: General (Box 43) and Newport News Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Company (Box 49).
  - Ficken, Katherine Cutler (Box 32)
  - Fields, Mitchell (Box 32)
  - Fillay, Hubert (Box 32)
  - Fine Arts Gallery of San Diego, See Poland, Reginald (Box 51).
  - Finkelstone, Douglas A. (Box 32)
  - Finley, John (Box 32)
  - Fiske, Bradley A. (Box 32)
  - FitzGerald, John D. (Box 32)
  - FitzHugh, Mayo McGill, includes photograph (Box 32)
  - Fitzmaurice-Kelly, James (Box 32)
  - Fleishhacker, Herbert, See California Palace of the Legion of Honor (San Francisco) (Box 16) and M. H. De Young Memorial Museum (San Francisco, Calif.) (Box 31).
  - Fleri, Joseph C. (Box 32)
  - Flint, Charles W. (Box 32)
    See also Syracuse University (Box 54).
  - Florence, South Carolina, proposal from town regarding a statue of Henry Timrod (Box 32)
  - Fogg Art Museum (Box 32)
  - Fontaine, Anne (Box 32)
  - Forbes, Edward W., See Fogg Art Museum (Box 32).
  - Forbes, John Ripley (Box 32)
  - Fort Ticonderoga Museum (Box 32)
  - Foulche-Delbosc, Isabel (Box 32)
  - Foundation for Alcohol Education (Box 32)
  - Fox, Beatrice, See Griffith, Beatrice Fox (Box 34).
  - Fox, John (Box 32)
  - Fradkin, James Jay (Box 32)
  - Franco, Francisco (Box 32)
  - Fraser, James Earle and Laura Gardin, includes photo of Laura as a small child (Box 32)
  - Freeman, Mary E. Wilkins (Box 32)
  - French, Daniel Chester (Box 32)
  - French, Frank (Box 32)
  - Frick, Helen C. (Box 32)
  - Friedlander, Leo, See National Sculpture Society (Box 48).
  - Frishmuth, Harriet Whitney (Box 32)
  - Fry, Fielding Lewis, See Brookgreen Gardens: General (Boxes 11-13).
  - Fuchs, Emil (Box 32)
  - Funck, Billy (Box 33)
  - F (Box 33)
  - Gallatin, Francis D. (Box 33)
  - Gallery of Modern Art (Box 33)
  - Garcia-Mazas, Jose and Maria Louisa, includes photographs, some of "The Torch-bearers"; typescript of essay about the Huntingtons entitled "The Spanish Saint Christopher"; see also; 2 folders (Box 33)
    See also Memorabilia: Miscellaneous: Garcia-Mazas (Box 86).
  - Gargani & Sons Art Studios, Inc. (Box 33)
  - Garland, Hamlin (Box 33)
  - Garshwiler, C. O., See Education Information, Inc. (Box 31).
  - Georgia Museum of Art (Box 33)
  - Gil, Enrique (Box 33)
  - Gilbert, Cass (Box 33)
  - Gilder, Joseph B. (Box 33)
  - Gillet, Joseph E. (Box 33)
  - Girl Scouts of America, See Siau, Nell (Box 53).
  - Glinsky, Vincent (Box 33)
  - Godoy, Armand (Box 33)
  - Goebel, Julius (Box 33)
  - Goldwater, Barry (Box 33)
  - Gomez, Alfonso (Box 33)
  - Gonzalez Marti, Manuel (Box 33)
  - Gordon, Elisabeth (Box 33)
  - Gorham Company (Box 33)
  - Grafly, Dorothy (daughter of Charles) (Box 33)
  - Grand Central Art Galleries (Box 33)
  - Greeley, Samuel A. (Box 33)
  - Green, Edward Mayo, See Christ Church Parish (Box 16).
  - Green, Irving (Box 33)
  - Greenbie, Marjorie Latta Barstow (Box 33)
  - Greenough, John (Box 34)
  - Greenville County Museum of Art (Greenville, S.C.) (Box 34)
  - Gregory, John (Box 34)
  - Gressel, Michael L. (Box 34)
  - Griffith, Beatrice Fox (Box 34)
  - Grinnell, George Bird (Box 34)
  - Griswold, Frank Gray (Box 34)
  - Gronvold, Magnus (Box 34)
  - Grummon, Stuart (Box 34)
  - Gruppe, Karl H. (Box 34)
  - Guell, Vizconde de (Box 34)
  - Gugler, Eric (Box 34)
  - G (Box 34)
  - Hadzsits, George Depue (Box 34)
  - Hagen, Sally (Box 34)
  - Hammond, Natalie H. (Box 34)
  - Hancock, Walker (Box 34)
  - Hanke, Lewis (Box 34)
    See also Library of Congress (Box 42).
  - Hapgood, George D. (Box 34)
  - Hardin, Adlai S. (Box 34)
  - Harrison, Henry B. (Box 34)
  - Hartford (Conn.) Department of Parks and Recreation (Box 34)
  - Hartford Art School (University of Hartford) (Box 34)
  - Hartgen, Vincent A. (Box 34)
  - Harvard University (Box 34)
    See also Fogg Art Museum (Box 32).
  - Hart, T. Stuart (Box 34)
  - Haseltine, Herbert (Box 34)
  - Hartley, Norah (Box 34)
  - Hatzfeldt, Clara and Hermann, Clara Elizabeth Huntington, adopted daughter of Collis (Box 34)
    See also Financial-Legal files: Hatzfeldt, Clara (Perkins) (Box 62).
  - Haug, Herman (Box 34)
  - Hay, Stuart and Maud, includes typescript of poem (Box 34)
  - Hayward, John and Mildred (Box 34)
    See also Hayward/Huntington/IBM Mediterranean exhibit (Box 35).
  - Hayward/Huntington/IBM Mediterranean exhibit, includes article by Emilio Costarelli (Box 35)
  - Hazard, Abbie and Margaret, includes original cartoon, hand colored (Box 35)
  - Hazen, Charles Downer (Box 35)
  - Hazen, Sally, 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Health Conservation Bureau (Box 35)
  - Hearst, Millicent (Box 35)
  - Heath, Howard (Box 35)
  - Heil, Walter, See California Palace of the Legion of Honor (San Francisco) (Box 16) and M. H. De Young Memorial Museum (San Francisco, Calif.) (Box 31).
  - Heye, George G., See Museum of the American Indian (Box 47).
  - Hiatt, Pearl Council, includes original poem about Brookgreen Gardens (Box 35)
  - Hickory Museum of Art (Box 35)
  - Hill, Nola (Mrs. Frederick F.)
    For Frederick F., see Mariners' Museum (Boxes 43 and 44).
  - Hills, Elijah Clare
  - Hindman, Albert (Box 35)
  - Hirsch, Willard, includes photographs of artwork (Box 35)
  - Hispanic Institute in Florida (Box 35)
  - Hispanic Institute in the United States (Box 35)
  - Hispanic Society of America
    - General
      - 1920-1954 (Box 35)
      - 1955-1966, 3 folders (Box 36)
      - Undated (Box 36)
    - Articles and reviews (Box 36)
    - Clippings, includes poem by Phyllis McGinley (Box 36)
    - Commemorative medal (Box 86)
    - Constitution, bylaws (Box 36)
    - General staff committee reports (Box 36)
    - Legal and financial files, See Legal and financial files: Hispanic Society of America (Box 62).
    - Lists (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 36)
    - Minutes (Box 36)
    - Photographic Archive of Hispanic Culture (proposal) (Box 36)
    - Photographs (Box 36)
      See also Memorabilia: Scrapbooks: Hispanic Society (Oversize 4). Many of the photographs are of Spanish art (sculpture, paintings, etc.) not of the HSA specifically.
    - Publications, 1915-1963; undated; 3 folders (Box 37)
  - Hispanic Society of Santa Barbara (Box 37)
  - Hitchcock, Charles B., See American Geographical Society (Box 8).
  - Hobson, Katherine Thayer (Box 37)
  - Hodgdon, Clara Hyatt ("Clarchen"), Alpheus III's daughter; See Kent, Clara Hyatt Hodgdon (Box 42).
  - Hodgdon, Jeanne, wife of Dana Hodgdon, Alpheus III's grandson (Box 37)
  - Hodge, Frederick W. (Box 37)
  - Hoffman, Edward, includes draft of letter of recommendation from AHH (Box 37)
  - Hoffman, Malvina (Box 37)
  - Holladay, Collis H. (Box 37)
    See also Newport News Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Company (Box 49).
  - Holladay, E. Burke (Mrs.) (Box 37)
  - Hood, Ethel P. (Box 37)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Box 37)
  - Hovey, Percy L., See Brookgreen Gardens: General (Boxes 11-13).
  - Howard, Cecil (Box 37)
  - Howells, John Mead, See American Academy of Arts and Letters (Boxes 7 and 8).
  - Howland, Elizabeth, includes original poetry (Box 37)
  - Hudson Valley Art Association (Box 37)
  - Hull, Cordell (Box 37)
  - Huntington Free Library and Reading Room (Box 37)
  - Huntington Galleries (Huntington, W. Va.) (Box 37)
  - Huntington, Archer Milton, from AHH (Box 37)
  - Huntington, Clara Elizabeth, adopted daughter of Collis; See Hatzfeldt, Clara and Hermann (Box 34).
  - Huntington, Collis Potter (Box 37)
  - Huntington, David (Box 37)
  - Huntington, Henry E. and Arabella, Archer's mother and stepfather (Box 37)
  - [Herny E.] Huntington Library and Art Gallery (Box 38)
  - Hyatt, Alpheus III, AHH's brother (Box 38)
  - Hyatt, Audella, AHH's mother; vast majority are to AHH
    - 1891-1910, 4 folders (Box 38)
    - 1911-1925, 13 folders (Box 39)
    - 1926-1932, 7 folders (Box 40)
    - Undated (Box 41)
    - Unidentified [?], AHH's mother (Box 41)
  - Hyatt, Clara ("Clarchen"), Alpheus III's daughter; See Kent, Clara Hyatt Hodgdon (Box 42).
  - Hyatt, Clara Carter, Alpheus III's widow; See Coad, Clara Carter Hyatt (Box 16).
  - Hyatt, Harriet, AHH's sister; See Mayor, Harriet Hyatt (Boxes 45 and 46)
  - Hyde, James Hazen (Box 41)
  - H, 2 folders (Box 41)
  - Instituto de Cultura Hispanica (Box 41)
  - Instituto de Valencia de Don Juan (Box 41)
  - International Fine-Arts Council, Inc. (Box 41)
  - International Who's Who (Box 41)
  - Isaacson, William D. (Box 41)
  - Italian-American Association for Sicily, Inc., See Hayward/Huntington/IBM Mediterranean exhibit (Box 35).
  - Ivan, Gus and Martha (Box 41)
  - Ives, Herbert E. and Mabel (Box 41)
    See also American Numismatic Society (Box 9).
  - I (Box 41)
  - Jacobson, Max (Box 41)
  - Jambor, Violet (Mrs. Louis) (Box 41)
  - Jennewein, Carl Paul (Box 41)
  - Joan of Arc Statue Committee of the City of New York, See Kunz, George Frederick (Box 42).
  - Johansen, John C., See National Arts Club (Box 48).
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood (Box 41)
  - Johnson, William Templeton (Box 41)
  - Jonas, Louis Paul (Box 41)
  - Jones, J. Morgan (Box 41)
  - J (Box 41)
  - Kelsey, Muriel Chamberlin (Box 41)
  - Kennerley, Mitchell, See Anderson Galleries (Box 9).
  - Kent, Clara Hyatt Hodgdon ("Clarchen"), Alpheus III's daughter (Box 42)
  - Kerner, Otto (Box 42)
  - Kilenyi, Julio, See International Fine-Arts Council, Inc. (Box 41).
  - Kimble, George H. T., See American Geographical Society (Box 8).
  - King, Georgiana Goddard (Box 42)
  - Krappe, Alexander Haggerty (Box 42)
  - Kunz, George Frederick (Box 42)
  - K (Box 42)
  - Ladd, Anna Coleman (Box 42)
  - Lalley, Tom and Helen (Box 42)
  - Lamar, Lucy (Box 42)
  - Lancaster County Historical Commission (Lancaster, S. C.) (Box 42)
  - Lane, Katherine, See Weems, Katherine Lane and Carrington (Box 57).
  - Lascari, Salvatore (Box 42)
  - Lathrop, Gertrude and Dorothy (Box 42)
  - Latty, Ruth K. (Box 42)
  - Lawrence, Helen Norbeck, includes original poetry (Box 42)
  - Lawrie, Lee (Box 42)
  - Leakey, Louis (Box 42)
  - Leavitt, Sturgis E. (Box 42)
  - Lee, Eleanor Gay (Box 42)
    See also:
    American Artists Professional League (Box 8)
    Burr Galleries (Box 15)
    Cassidy, Appolonia (Box 16)
    Daughters of the American Revolution (Box 18)
    Art files: Pickett, Grace (Box 3).
  - Leon, Walter (Box 42)
  - Letsch, Dorothy, includes original poem about "Sybil Ludington's Ride," read at dedication (Box 42)
  - Lever, Hardman ("Sam") and Edythe (Box 42)
  - Lewis, Mary (Mrs. Edward) (Box 42)
  - Library of Congress (Box 42)
    See also Putnam, Herbert (Box 51).
  - Library of Suppressed Facts and Controversial Opinions (Box 42)
  - Lie, Jonas (Box 42)
  - Light, Richard U., See American Geographical Society (Box 8).
  - Ligon, Maurine (Box 42)
  - Lincoln City (Oregon) (Box 42)
    See also Greenbie, Marjorie Latta Barstow (Box 33).
  - Lists
    - Institutions (Box 42)
    - Mailing (Box 42)
    - People (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 42)
  - Litchfield Hills Audobon Society, See Egler, Frank E. (Box 31).
  - Lober, Georg (Box 42)
  - Lockman, De Witt M. (Box 42)
    See also Photographs: Artwork by others: Lockman, DeWitt M. (Oversize 1)
  - Lodge, John Davis (Box 42)
  - London Library (Box 42)
  - Long, Georgia (Box 43)
  - Louderback, Walt (Box 43)
  - Loughrey, Hylda (Box 43)
  - L (Box 43)
  - Mackay, Clarence Hungerford (Box 43)
  - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 43)
  - MacLeod, Yan (Box 43)
  - MacNeil, Hermon Atkins (Box 43)
  - Mallory, Clifford D. and Rebecca (Box 43)
  - Manca, Albino (Box 43)
  - Mann, Julie Manierre (Box 43)
  - Manship, Paul and Isabel, includes pictures of his sculpture (photocopies) (Box 43)
  - Mapother, Edith Rubel, includes photographs (Box 43)
  - Maps
    - Blue Mountain Lake, Township 34, New York, 1899 (Box 43)
    - Harwinton (Connecticut) (Box 43)
    - Messina (Italy), Raccordi Ferroviari [Railway Connections] (Box 43)
    - Newcomb Quadrangle (New York), 1869 (Box 43)
    - Pacific Ocean, 1936 (Box 43)
    - Raquette Lake (New York), hand-drawn and hand-colored (Box 43)
  - Marans, Moissaye (Box 43)
  - Margaret Brent Fellowship, See Greenbie, Marjorie Latta Barstow (Box 33).
  - Marine Historical Association, Inc. (Box 43)
    See also Mallory, Clifford D. and Rebecca (Box 43).
  - Mariners' Museum (Newport News, Va.)
    - General, 1931-1957; undated; 3 folders (Box 43)
    - Attendance and progress reports (Box 44)
    - Bank statements (Box 44)
    - Charts and pictures (Box 44)
    - Minutes (Box 44)
    - Photographs, 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Presidential reports (Box 44)
    - Printed material
      - Articles (Box 44)
      - Clippings (Box 44)
    - Trust (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 44)
  - Markham, Edwin (Box 44)
  - Marshall, Caroline Clark, includes typescripts of two poems (Box 44)
  - Marshall, Ernest M., includes typescript of poem, "The Whaler" (Box 44)
  - Massip, Jose Maria y Ramon (Box 44)
  - Mather, Frank Jewett (Box 44)
  - Mattatuck Historical Society (Box 44)
  - Maurin, Joaquin (Box 44)
  - Mayne, Elizabeth (Box 44)
  - Mayor, A. Hyatt and Virginia (Sluder), son Alfred, AHH's nephew and his wife (Box 44)
  - Mayer, Alfred Goldsborough, AHH's brother-in-law, Harriet Hyatt Mayor's husband (Box 44)
  - Mayor, Barbara, AHH's niece; See Money, Barbara Mayor (Box 46).
  - Mayor, Brantz and Ana Maria; children Maria and "O.E." (Archer Huntington Mayor), 1946-1967; undated; AHH's nephew and his second wife (Box 45)
  - Mayor, Brantz and Evelyn; daughter Susie, 1928-1946; AHH's nephew and his first wife (Box 45)
  - Mayor, Harriet Hyatt (Mrs. Alfred Goldsborough), AHH's sister
    - 1901-1932, 1936-1952, 6 folders (Box 45)
    - 1953-1955, 1961, undated, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Mayor, Katharine, AHH's niece; See Townsend, Katherine Mayor Cook (Box 55).
  - Mayor, Michael and Lili, Brantz and Evelyn's son and daughter-in-law (Box 46)
  - Mazas family, See Garcia-Mazas, Jose and Maria Louisa (Box 33).
  - McAlister, A.W., includes original poem (Box 46)
  - McCartan, Edward (Box 46)
  - McCormick-Goodharte, Leander and Nita (Box 46)
  - McFarland, Russell M. (Box 46)
  - McKenzie, Robert Tait (Box 46)
  - McKinnon, Annie (Box 46)
  - McLean, Ethel (Box 46)
  - McMahon, Leonard (Box 46)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 46)
  - Mechlin, Leila (Box 46)
  - Medallic Art Company (Box 46)
  - Medical College of Virginia (Richmond, Va.) (Box 46)
  - Mellon, Eleanor M., includes photo of her sculpture (Box 46)
  - Mencia, Armando (Box 46)
  - Menconi, Ralph J. (Box 46)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 46)
  - Meylan, Paul J. (Box 46)
  - Le Mérite National Francais (Box 46)
  - Mezquita, Lopez (Box 46)
  - Mid-Fairfield County Youth Museum, See Forbes, John Ripley (Box 32).
  - Miles, George C., See American Numismatic Society (Box 9).
  - Millar, Donal, includes original poem (Box 46)
  - Millard, Anita (Box 46)
  - Millikan, Robert A. (Box 46)
  - Milton Academy (Box 46)
  - Minor, Charles (Box 46)
  - Money, Barbara Mayor, AHH's niece (Box 46)
  - Monjo, Enrique (Box 47)
  - Montana, Pietro (Box 47)
  - Moore, Austin T., includes photograph (Box 47)
  - Moore, John Bassett (Box 47)
  - Moore-Anderson, Nora, includes photographs; letters from England during World War II (Box 47)
  - Morgan, J. Pierpont (Box 47)
  - Morgan, Sherley W. (Box 47)
  - Morrison, Bill (Box 47)
  - Morton, Benjamin (Box 47)
  - Morton, Christina (Box 47)
  - Mosier, Helen (Mrs. W.B.) (Box 47)
  - Mount Rushmore National Memorial Commission, See Borglum, Gutzon (Box 11).
  - Museo Sorolla, See Sorolla, Joaquin (Box 54).
  - Museum of the American Indian (Box 47)
  - Museum of Art, Science & Industry (Bridgeport, Conn.) (Box 47)
  - Museum of Fine Arts (St. Petersburg, Fla.) (Box 47)
  - Museum of the City of New York (Box 47)
  - Museums of the Peaceful Arts, See Kunz, George Frederick (Box 42.)
  - Myers, George Hewitt (Box 47)
  - Myrtle Beach Air Force Base (Box 47)
  - Mystic Seaport, See Marine Historical Association, Inc. (Box 43).
  - M, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Nadelman, Elie (Box 47)
  - National Academy of Design (Box 48)
  - National Art Museum of Sport Inc. (Box 48)
  - National Arts Club (Box 48)
  - National Arts Foundation (Box 48)
  - National Battlefields Commission (Quebec) (Box 48)
  - National Foundation for Junior Museums, See Forbes, John Ripley (Box 32).
  - National Hall of Fame for Famous American Indians (Box 48)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 48)